Last name/Name	González Esteban, Sergio	
Address	Mateo de Torres 4 Street.	
Post Code	28806	
Town/City	Alcalá de Henares, Madrid, Spain.	
Date of birth	15 th January 1989	
Mobile Phone	(+0034)626933136	
Driving license	category B	
E-mail	sergiogonzalezesteban@gmail.com	



Motivated and dynamic engineer dedicated to telecommunications systems. Talent to design, test and be responsible for the maintenance of RF, microwave systems and avionics Systems. Strong background and experience working with aeronautical and data acquisition systems, electrical system, antennas and sensors. Ability to run military defense equipment such as Identification Friend and Foe and Automatic Identification boats

SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

- Two years of experience testing the different equipment of Unmanned Aerial vehicle.
- Broad knowledge working with aeronautical equipment.
- Extensive experience and understanding of RF, data links, microwaves and telecommunications system based on military frequencies.
- Audio Systems and recording systems of aircrafts. System specialist and designer.
- Solid understanding of ground control station.
- Knowledge of STANAGS 7085, 4586, DO 160 and DO178.
- Knowledge of Aeronautical Communication 1553B and ARINC 429
- Able to resolve complex technical issues related to defense projects and aeronautical systems, like other UAS (unmanned aerial systems) and it's Ground Control Stations.
- Computer skills include: office, Matlab & Simulink, CST, genesis and C language. Good user knowledge of all Microsoft operating systems.
- Knowledge of Airbus documents and company tools (DOORS, airbus supply, e-room, ishare, synergy...)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AIRBUS MILITARY.2013

COMMS A400M - Systems Engineer (June 2013-Actual)

- Reviewing and developing of documentation of A400M communication equipment. Supplier and Airbus internal documentation
- System Specialist of audio systems and recording systems.
- o System Specialist of telecommunication systems (direction finder and HF Radio).
- o System verification and validation.
- Testing in laboratory and in ground the different systems.

- Supporting flight test.
- Reviewing and solving problems opened during flight, ground or laboratory tests.

INDRA SISTEMAS. 2012-2013 Madrid, Spain. 2011 -2012

Telecommunications engineer. Internship contract.

UAV PELICANO - Systems engineer (2011-2013)

- o Tested a helicopter's electrical system.
- Executed tests cases and configuring the application of UAV equipment for operation (external battery, Power supply unit, power distribution).
- o Developed a new electrical system.
- o Reviewed and comparing the telemetry of an UAV.
- Used control and monitoring (Ground Control Station)
- Took part and testing the different equipment of helicopter (AIS, IFF, Data links, Aeronautical System Data and electrical system)
- Gave support to the project team and the person responsible for testing the UAV. Responsible of link budget. Coverage analysis and design of Ground data terminal
- Took an active part in another unmanned aerial system (aircraft) as a systems engineer.
- o Supported and configured RF and data links for other unmanned aerial system.

EDUCATION

	Date	September 2007 - June 2012
Qualified Telecommunications engineer.	Place	Polytechnic school. University of Alcala, Madrid, Spain.
	Degree Project	Omnidirectional antenna for mobile communication
Master's degree:	Date	September 2012 - march 2013
Development	Place	Alcalá de henares
management.		CIFF (Alcalá de Henares)

LANGUAGES

LANGUAGES	Level
Spanish	Mother tongue
English	Fluent
French	Basic